Hassan EL-KHARROUBI

🗣 Fes, Morocco 🗷 elkharroubihassan@outlook.com 🔲 (212)653299019 🛅 in/hassanelkharroubi 🛥 github.com/hassanelkharroubi

SUMMARY

Data scientist with 1 year of experience in data analysis and data modeling. Experienced in data mining, data visualization, machine learning, and Deep Learning. Skilled in designing and developing automated data and modeling pipelines, building predictive models, and optimizing business processes.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer

Technocolabs

September 2022 - Present, India

- · Scraping data from various sources (No API) using Python and Selenium.
- · Data Cleaning and Visualisation using Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, GGplot, and Geoplotlib.
- · Performing statistical analysis and using results to improve models.
- · Designing, developing, and researching Machine Learning systems.

Development of Algorithms for Dematerialization Of Cham - French Dictionary

Computer, Image and Interaction Laboratory (L3i)

March 2022 - August 2022, France, La Rochelle

- · Realization of one of the phases of the ANR Chamdoc project.
- · Creation of a database of CHAM words and expressions as well as their transcription and translation.
- · Using Computer Vision techniques.
- · Using Deep Learning, Machine Learning, and Transfer Learning for Document Layout Analysis, word classification into 3 categories (languages), and Chams letter recognition.

SKILLS

Industry Knowledge: Data Science, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Image Processing, Optical Character Recognition (OCR), Data Analysis, Business intelligence, Android Development, Linux System Administration, Web Development, Project Management.

Tools & Technologies: Python, SQL, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, CAFFE, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Java, C/C++, Microsoft Excel, JavaScript, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau

Interpersonal Skills: Collaboration, Communication, Leadership, Perseverance

Languages: English(Proficient), Arabic (Native), French(Proficient)

EDUCATION

Master degree in Web Intelligence and Data Science

Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah University · Morocco, Fez · 2022

Master degree in Data Mining and Business Intelligence Sorbonne Paris Nord University • France, Villetaneuse • 2022

Bachelor's degree in Mathematics and Computer Science

Sidi Mohammed Ben Abdellah University · Morocco, Fez · 2020

PROJECTS

Predicting Mortgage Backed Securities Prepayment Using Machine Learning

December 2022 - January 2023

- · Data Cleaning using Python and Pandas.
- · Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) using Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn.
- · Performing statistical analysis to improve models.
- · Modeling using different Machine Learning algorithms.
- · Using CNN for feature extraction.

Sentiments Analysis: The War Between Russia And Ukraine

January 2022 - April 2022

- · Scrapping Data from social media using Python and Selenium plus Twitter API.
- · Labeling data manually into 3 classes (positive, neutral, negative).
- · Processing data for removing stop words, other languages than French ...
- · Feature extraction using BERT and FastText.

Traffic Signs Classification using Deep Learning & Machine Learning

January 2022 - February 2022

- · Building an application for traffic signs with a dataset containing 34799 images and 43 classes.
- · Applying image processing techniques as contrast enhancement.
- Feature extraction for Machine Learning part as shape features and edge features.
- · Using CNN with transfer Learning (ImageNet) for traffic sign classification.

Sentiment Analysis for Moroccan Dialect

October 2021 - January 2022

- · Project aims to analyze vaccination Moroccan opinions.
- · Scrapping Data from social media using Python and Selenium.
- · Labeling data manually into 2 classes.
- Feature extraction using AraBERT and Word embedding.
- Leading my team to achieve the 3rd position in this competition.

INVOLVEMENT

Member

Rifq Center for Scientifc Research • February 2018 - Present

- Participated in forums and discussions within groups of Rifq center.
- · Giving lectures in the field of computer science and Learning Methodologies.
- · Science Branch Team Leader for RIfq center.